Nick So UX Designer

www.nickso.com contact@nickso.com linkedin.com/in/nick-so San Diego, CA

Over 8 years of experience designing games, apps, websites, and other digital media. Multiple commercial experiences shipped for web and mobile devices. Organized, amicable, and versatile. Let's create something amazing.

SKILLS

Technical - Adobe CC || Figma || HTML5 || CSS || Javascript || Bootstrap || JQuery **UX** - User Research || Personas || Storyboards || Wireframing || Rapid Prototyping **Production** - Agile/Scrum || Trello || JIRA || Confluence || Remote Collaboration

EXPERIENCE

Designer (December 2018 - Present)

Redemption Games (Carlsbad, CA - Remote)

- Designing gameplay for Sweet Escapes
- Over 250 shipped designs

Design Consultant (February 2019 - March 2020)

Awairness, Inc (Santa Fe, NM - Remote)

- Worked alongside company leadership to refine the design of *OneNova*
- Designed and documented development tools and core game systems
- Prototyped user interface and first-time user experience
- Created design templates and modular development tools
- Advised on various aspects of game design & team development
- Assisted with production and development planning

Senior Game Designer (May 2015 - November 2018)

Jam City (Carlsbad, CA - On-Site)

- Managed day-to-day tasks and long-term roadmap for 20-person design team
- Facilitated weekly design meetings and content reviews
- Collaborated on designs to increase user retention and conversion by over 10%
- Designed and shipped numerous gameplay features for the Cookie Jam franchise
- Created over 700 level designs for Cookie Jam & Cookie Jam Blast
- Wrote core design documentation for unannounced projects

PROJECTS

California Innocence Project UX Case Study (2021)

Role: Designer || Time Frame: 2 Weeks || Team Size: 4 || Tools: Figma, Miro, Trello nickso.com/ux-design/casestudylink

Re-imagining the non-profit's website for the modern era of the internet, with a focus on social media engagement and contemporary aesthetics.

Second UX Case Study (2021)

Role: Designer || Time Frame: 2 Weeks || Team Size: 4 || Tools: Figma, Miro, Trello nickso.com/ux-design/casestudylink

Second UX Case Study description that will definitely be filled in when I actually do it.

OneNova Game & UX Design (2020)

Role: Lead Designer | Time Frame: 12 months | Team Size: 2 |

Tools: Balsamiq, Photoshop, InVision, Trello, Slack, Google Workspace

onenovathegame.com/ (Work samples unavailable due to NDA)

Designed and documented the mechanics of gameplay and progression systems.

Prototyped the first-time user experience along with core menus, modals, and interfaces.

Discovered and refined UI elements and overall visual design.

RoboRunner Design Document Sample (2020)

Role: Lead Designer | Time Frame: 1 Week | Team Size: 1 | Tools: Balsamiq, Photoshop sites.google.com/view/robo-runner

RoboRunner is an educational game designed to help young children learn the basics of computer programming, specifically mastering the concept functions. This is a small sample of my game design documentation. Art styles vary from game-to-game.

EDUCATION

UX/UI Design Certificate

University of California, Irvine (2021)

Bachelor of Arts, Film & Digital Media Production

University of California, Santa Cruz (2012)